<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DataPlatform Franchising</title><link href="http://datapfranc.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://datapfranc.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://datapfranc.github.io/</id><updated>2016-04-14T11:15:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Why Book Review?</title><link href="http://datapfranc.github.io/misc/brd_why/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-14T11:15:00+02:00</published><author><name>Martin Ouellet</name></author><id>tag:datapfranc.github.io,2016-04-14:misc/brd_why/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- Status: draft --&gt;

&lt;h3 id="passion"&gt;Passion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep on working on any personal project you need motivation, that's a given. Without any constraints or external pressure to work on something, what else can help you maintain motivation? Are factors like potential gain, popularity or recognition enough? Answer from personal experience: no.. these probably help at the beginning, but on the long run they'll leave you unfulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what else can bring you lasting motivation? One word: &lt;strong&gt;passion&lt;/strong&gt;! Working on stuff compatible with interest makes work less like &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; and more like &lt;em&gt;leisure&lt;/em&gt;! Personally, I enjoy working on data-oriented projects. So I only need ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/!--&gt;</summary><category term="BRD"></category></entry><entry><title>How to do data integration, BRD example</title><link href="http://datapfranc.github.io/misc/BRD_DI_part1/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-01T11:15:00+02:00</published><author><name>Martin Ouellet</name></author><id>tag:datapfranc.github.io,2016-04-01:misc/BRD_DI_part1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3 id="data-integration-one-of-the-main-bi-functions"&gt;Data Integration: one of the main BI functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designing proper and cohesive architecture is key to BI project success. Unfortunately, business is pressuring technical teams for quick delivery, and IT jumps straight to designing star schema or dimensional models (the &lt;strong&gt;presentation layer&lt;/strong&gt;), and neglect the &lt;strong&gt;integration layer&lt;/strong&gt;.  End result: no separation of concerns will exist between the integration AND presentation aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integration and Presentation are two critical functions of BI and must be decoupled into separate layers (at least logically) reflecting their independent goals and specifications. I've documented my choice of architecture   &lt;a href="http://martin-ouellet.blogspot.ch/2013/08/bi-ideal-platform.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), this post only discusses the data ...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BRD"></category><category term="data integration"></category></entry></feed>